Andrew Cartwright

Full-Stack Software Engineer in Birmingham, AL, specializing in TypeScript, React, and Node.js. Passionate about Arduino projects and Linux. Enthusiastic mentor who enjoys gardening, cooking, woodworking, hiking, and spending time with pets.

Birmingham, AL andrewlloydcartwright@gmail.com https://atlc.dev https://github.com/atlc

EXPERIENCE

Covalence, Remote — Software Developer / Lead Instructor

2020 - PRESENT

Led full-stack web development bootcamp, provided personalized 1-on-1 student mentorship, actively developed and maintained curriculum, and produced public programming tutorials.

Hubbard Systems, Remote — Devops Engineer

2019 - 2020

Started DevOps department, automated internal processes, created CI/CD pipelines for a COBOL+Java+Electron/React app, and developed devtools and documentation system.

Vincari, Birmingham — *Software Engineer*

2016 - 2017

Worked on our legacy EMR application in a rebuild phase, performing both bug fixes and developing new features, including creating a logging and analytics system.

Hubbard Systems, Birmingham — Application System Analyst

2015 - 2016

Provided training and support for our accounting application, and performed Windows, Linux, and MS SQL server administration.

EDUCATION

A.S. Mathematics, Jefferson State Community College

2024

Mu Alpha Theta member & obtained a 3.3 GPA in my math courses, including Cal I, II, III, Statistics, Differential Equations, & Linear Algebra.

A.S. CIS - Programming, Jefferson State Community College

2017

The recipient of the 2016 College Scholars award

SKILLS

TypeScript, React, Node.js, ES6+
JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, mobile
responsive design, Tailwind, Bootstrap,
MaterialUI, styled-components, Stripe,
Square, Mailgun, Mailchimp, auth,
Passport.js, JWTs, RESTful API design,
Relational SQL (mainly Postgres and
MySQL), NoSQL (primarily MongoDB),
key-value DBs (primarily Redis),
python, C++, Arduino, Linux, git, AWS,
Azure, Heroku, DigitalOcean, Devops,
Jenkins

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft:

- Azure Fundamentals
- MTA Software Development
- MTA Database Administration
- MTA Security Fundamentals

AWS:

- Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Certified Developer (expected August 2024)

Linux Professional Institute:

- Linux Essentials
- LPIC-1 (expected August 2024)

CompTIA:

- Healthcare IT Technician